(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T01:46:34.402676",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いつも口からでまかせばかりしゃべってる
You're always talking nonsense right off the top of your head.
イエスノーどちらでもないこともあるでしょう
There must be times when it's neither yes nor no.
いつだって世界は私を楽しくさせて
The world is always making me have fun,
いつか動かなくなる時まで遊んでね
so let's play until we can't move anymore.
しゃくしゃく余裕で暮らしたい
I want to live leisurely and relaxed,
約束だって守りたい
and keep my promises too.
誰かを愛すことなんて
Loving someone else...
本当はとても簡単だ
is actually really easy.
ずいぶん遠くまで流れ流れてせつないんです
Washing away so far off makes me feel so bittersweet.
大事な思い出さえ忘れていきそうで
I feel like I'm going to forget even my precious memories.
確かな君に会いたい
I want to see you for sure.
百年先も傍にいたい
I want to be by your side a hundred years from now.
どんなに離れ離れでも
No matter how far apart we might be,
ふたりをつなぐ呪文は J・O・Y
the spell that connects us is J-O-Y.
櫟の木が揺れる日は、
On days when the oak trees sway,
すぐに思い出してね。私を。
remember me right away. Me.
いつも口からでまかせばかりしゃべってる
You're always talking nonsense right off the top of your head.
運命は必然じゃなく偶然で出来てる
Destiny isn't inevitable; it's made of coincidences.
いつまで経ってもわかんない
I still don't get it no matter how long passes,
約束だって破りたい
and I even want to break my promises.
誰かを愛すことなんて
Loving someone else...
時々とても困難だ
is sometimes really difficult.
確かな君に会いたい
I want to see you for sure.
百年先も傍にいたい
I want to be by your side a hundred years from now.
どんなに離れ離れでも
No matter how far apart we might be,
ふたりをつなぐ呪文は J・O・Y
the spell that connects us is J-O-Y.
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to race until I die.
死ぬまでワクワクしたいわ
I want to be thrilled until I die.
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to race until I die.
死ぬまでワクワクしたいわ
I want to be thrilled until I die.
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to race until I die.
はい、というわけで、みんな、ハローロボ！
Hi, so everyone, Hello Robo!
ホロライブ零期生、バーチャルロボットのロボ子だよー！
I'm Roboco, a virtual robot of Hololive 0th generation!
グッドモーニング、グッドアフタヌーン、グッドイブニング！
Good morning, good afternoon, good evening!
おら、ロボ！みんな、いっぱい拍手ありがとうございます！
Hello, Robo! Thank you all so much for the applause!
というわけでね、本日はこちら、 #ロボ子さん3Dバラードライブ で呟いていってください！
So today, please tweet using the hashtag #Roboco3DBalladLive!
というわけでね、改めてまして、えー、ロボ子がずっとやってみたかった、えっと、今日、今日ね、なんとね、あのマスクをしたままこう、喋りながらやってるんだけど、このバーチャルマスクね（笑）
So, to reiterate, um, something Roboco has always wanted to do... wait, today, you know, I'm actually talking while wearing a mask, this virtual mask, haha!
そうなんですけれども、なんとね、水を飲みます、ちょっと待ってね。
That being said, you know... I'm going to drink some water, hold on a second.
はい、というわけで、えー、ロボ子がね、ずーっとやってみたかった3Dのバラードライブが、やっとできるということで、
Right, so, um, the 3D ballad live that Roboco has always wanted to do is finally happening,
もう、すごいね、嬉しかったんだけど、ちょうどロボ子が咽喉をね、壊してた時期でもあったので、もうめちゃくちゃ不安だったんだけれども、
and I was so, so happy, but it was also right around the time when I strained my throat, so I was super anxious,
でも、今日はまだ声が出るほうだとう思うので、ぜひ、もうロボ子は今の状況で精一杯頑張って歌っていくので、
but I think my voice is still holding up well today, so please, Roboco will do her absolute best in this condition to sing,
みんな、ぜひぜひ聴いてみてください！
everyone, please, please listen!
もう、3周年もやって、そうなんです、ロボ子3周年、そう、3周年ライブの3月9日には配信ができなかったんだけど、
We're also doing 3 years... that's right, Roboco's 3rd anniversary, well, we couldn't broadcast the 3rd anniversary live on March 9th,
振り返りということでね、本日にリスケでやることができました！嬉しい！
so as a look back, we were able to reschedule and do it today! I'm so happy!
うれせー、むりせず頑張れ、いえー、てきゅう！みんな聴いてってくれるか？どうだ？おー！がんばれ！バラードのみんなありがとう！
Yay, "do your best without pushing yourself", yeah, thank you! Will everyone listen? How's that? Oh! Do your best! Thank you everyone for the ballad!
もう、そんなにね、たつんですよ。
It's been already that long, you know.
めちゃくちゃ綺麗だった。
It was super pretty.
そう、1曲目は、実ロボ子がね、あの、結構前から好きだったJOYのね、え、雪の曲をね、歌わせていただきました。
Yes, for the first song, actually, Roboco sang a snow song by JOY, which I've loved for quite a while now.
めちゃくちゃ明るい曲でね、いいでしょ？で、まあバラードだからね、あの、まあ、
It's a super bright song, right? And well, since it's a ballad, um, well,
明るい曲もまあまあいいなって思った、あ、そう、Gorsettoね、あの同期なんですよ。えへへ、えへへ、えへへ、そうなんですよね。
I thought bright songs are also nice, oh right, Gorsetto, um, we're generation mates. Ehehe, that's right.
そうなんですけど、まあね、やっぱバラードって言ったら悲しい曲、いいじゃないですか。
That's true, but you know, when you say ballad, sad songs are nice too, right?
ロボ子、好きな曲があるんですよ。あの、奥華子さんの曲なんですけど、作詞作曲曲が、そう。
Roboco has a song she loves. Um, it's a song by Okui Hanako, written and composed by her, yes.
ちょっと、あの、すっごい切ない曲歌ってもいいですか？ちょっと泣いちゃうかもしれないけど、いいですか？ちょっと泣いちゃうかもしれない、ハンカチの用意をしてくれたらいいなって思います。
Um, can I sing a really heartbreaking song? I might cry a bit, is that okay? I might cry a bit, so I hope you can have a handkerchief ready.
というわけで、それではじゃあ次の曲をね、聴いてください。え、好きな人、お願いします。
With that said, please listen to the next song. Um, "Sukina Hito", please.
好きな人は あなただった
The person I loved was you.
もうこれ以上 優しくしないで
Please don't be this gentle anymore.
あなたは友達の 好きな人
You are the person my friend loves.
応援すると 決めたのに
Even though I decided to support you both,
苦しくなる 気持ちが隠せない
I can't hide this painful feeling.
天気いいから
Since the weather's nice,
ちょっと窓でも開けて
I'll open the window just a bit,
風に吹かれて 知らぬ知らぬ鼻歌
Breeze in my hair, humming a tune unawares,
床の陽だまり 猫にひっついて
Cuddling up to the cat in a patch of sunlight,
寝転んで丸まってお昼寝しよう
I'll curl up and take a nap.
好きな人は あなただった
The person I love was you...
私の心は あなたでした
My heart belonged to you.
気付くふたりは お似合いだよと
Saying the two of us look so good together,
平気な顔して 嘘をつく
Putting on a brave face and telling lies,
何もできずに 見ているだけの
Unable to do anything but just watch,
弱虫な私って 大嫌い
I hate how cowardly I am.
叶わない恋だと知ってても
Even knowing it's an unrequited love,
この気持ちすぐには捨てられない
I can't throw away these feelings just yet.
あの頃にはもう戻れない
We can never go back to those days,
あなたがこの胸の中 溢れてくるの
And you overflow inside my heart.
泣きたいほど好きになって
I grew to love you enough to cry,
泣けないほど苦しかった
And suffered enough that I couldn't even weep.
泣きたいのは私だって 恋をしてたのは私でした
I was the one who wanted to cry, the one who was in love.
もしも一つだけ願えるのなら 一度でいいから
If I could make just one wish, even if only once,
あなたの好きな人になりたい
I want to be the person that you love.
好きな人は あなただった
The person I love was you...
私の心は あなたでした
My heart belonged to you.
はい、というわけで、え、好きな人でした。
Yes, so that was... um, "Suki na Hito".
どうでしたか？パチパチたくさん、ありがとう！嬉しい！
How was it? Lots of applause, thank you! I'm so happy!
この曲はね、そう、ロボ子が好きな失恋曲なんです。
This song is... well, one of Roboco's favorite heartbreak songs.
ロボ子が好きって言うとちょっと、なんか誤解があるんですけれどね。
Though when I say Roboco's "favorite," there might be a bit of a misunderstanding.
そう、これいいよね、すごいさ、気持ちに迫ってくる感じなんだよね。「好きな人って」あー、あーってなるよね、バラードになっていく。
Right, it's so good. It really presses right into your feelings. "The person I love..." You go "Ah... ah..." as it turns into a ballad.
ありえ、泣いてますよ。今日はね、バラードライブなんだね、みんなのこともね、泣かせてもらって、ん？泣かしてもらったり、笑ってもらったりしてもらえたら嬉しいよ、つってさ。なんか泣いてきた、嬉しい。そう。
Seriously, I'm crying. Today is a ballad live, so if I can make you all cry—hm? Make you cry, make you smile, I'd be so happy. Somehow I'm starting to cry, I'm so happy. Yeah.
この、この後ろに、後ろに掲げある
This, behind me, displayed behind me...
このロボットメモリーっていうね、ロボ子についてくるんだってなっちゃったけど、
This "Robot Memory"... well, it ended up following Roboco, but...
このロボットメモリーっていうことでね、まあ、ロボコのね、配信で歌った曲がほとんどなんだけど、
With "Robot Memory," well, most of the songs are ones Roboco sang on her streams, but...
ま、そんな中でも1部1部はみんなライブとかでの思い出の曲も入った感じの思い出の曲をね、歌っていこうと思ったので、
Among them, I decided to sing some memorable songs, including ones with memories from lives, so...
せっかくだからね、ロボ子やりたかったロボット、ロボットの…、なんか緊張しきっちゃった、バラードライブだったのね、
Since we have the chance, Roboco wanted to do a robot... wait, I got all nervous, it was a ballad live, you see,
ロボットメモリーっていうねタイトルをね、大々的につけてみました！
so I gave it the grand title "Robot Memory"!
可愛くない？そう、初めはちょっとなんか色々悩んで違うのになってたんだけど、
Isn't it cute? Yeah, at first I was agonizing over various things and it was going to be different, but...
ちょっと待って
Wait a minute...
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あれ、これ、声聞こえてるのかな？
Huh? Is my voice audible?
そう、ロボットメモリーっていうね、曲でロゴも可愛いでしょう？
Yeah, with the song "Robot Memory," the logo is cute too, right?
そうなんですよね。
That's right, you know.
あれ、運営さんって今、あれ、これもうずっと声聞こえてるのかなもしみんな、どうかなこれ、聞こえてる？
Huh? Management right now... Huh, has my voice been audible this whole time? Can you hear it?
あれ、あの…
Huh? Um...
いや違う、あ、みんなごめん！
No wait, ah, everyone sorry!
今本当は聞こえてないのが正しくて、あのロボ子が、あの、咳き込みたい時とか、
Actually, it's correct that you couldn't hear it, when Roboco wanted to cough or something,
してる時にあの運営さんに、この、こうやって音をちょっと消してもらいたいんですけどっていう、あの、アイスを出してたんだけども、
when doing that, I was giving management an "ice" [signal] asking them to please turn off the sound like this,
あれ、ミュートになってないかも知れん、どっちだっけって、今ちょっとね、あの、焦ってしまったので、聞きもしました
but I wondered if it wasn't muted, which one was it? I panicked just now, so I asked.
そう、咳払い音をね、ちょっとばれないように、あの、してたんだけど、あ、ばれちゃったな。
Yeah, I was doing that so the throat-clearing sound wouldn't be noticed, but ah, it got noticed.
ああ、そういうこともあるよね
Ah, those things happen too.
そう、ハンドサインが実はあったんですよ。
Yeah, there actually was a hand sign.
うん、いや、バレてしまったら仕方がない。
Hmm, well, if it got noticed, it can't be helped.
じゃあ次もね、切ない曲をね、歌っていきたいと思いますので、ぜひぜひ聴いてください。
Well, next I'll be singing another heartbreaking song, so please listen.
みんなのつぶやきも、スクショもいっぱい来てくれると嬉しいよ。ピース！
I'd be happy if you post lots of tweets and screenshots too. Peace!
っていうわけで、それでは聴いてください。「ホームラ…」
That being said, well then, please listen. "Homu..."
さようなら ありがとう 声の限り
Goodbye and thank you, as loud as my voice can reach
悲しみよりもっと 大事なこと
Something much more important than sadness
去り行く背中に 伝えたくて
I wanted to convey to your departing back
ぬくもりと痛みに 間に合うように
So that I could make it in time for the warmth and pain
このまま続くと思っていた
I thought it would continue just like this
僕らの明かりを描いていた
We were painting our tomorrows
呼び合っていた光がまだ 胸の奥に熱いのに
The light we called out to is still hot deep in our chests, yet
僕たちは燃え盛る旅の途中で出会い
We met on our burning journey
手を取りそして離した 未来のために
Passed hands and parted ways, for the future
夢が一つ叶うたび 僕は君を想うだろう
Whenever one of my dreams comes true, I'll think of you
強くありたいと願い 泣いた 決意を頬に
Wishing to become stronger, tears of resolve on my cheeks
懐かしい思いに囚われたり 残酷な世界に泣き叫んで
Trapped in nostalgic memories, crying out in this cruel world
大人になるほど増えて行く
The more I grow up, the more they increase
もう何ひとつだって失いたくない
I don't want to lose a single thing more
悲しみに飲み込まれ果てしてしまえば
If I were consumed by sadness and lost myself
痛みを 感じなくなるけれど
I wouldn't feel the pain anymore, but
君の言葉 君の願い 僕は守り抜くと誓ったんだ
Your words, your wish, I swore to protect them
面倒だと思いながら
Even though you thought that it was a bother,
君は僕にキスをした
you leaned down to kiss me.
泣き止まない 雨は穏やか
The rain didn't stop, it kept crying peacefully.
傘を閉じて 二人濡れた
I closed the umbrella, and we stood there wet.
その声にもう少し 抱かれていれたなら
I wish that your voice could embrace me a bit longer.
愛してる？ 今す少し 口が止まったけれど
Do you love me? My answer came just a second late.
叫んだ想いは きっと雨と一緒に 排水溝へ流れゆく
These feelings that I shout out will soon go down the drain with the rain.
どれだけ素敵な 歌にせたって 届かない
It doesn't matter what beautiful song I sing, it won't reach you.
手を伸ばし 抱き留めた 激しい光の束
I reached out and caught a bundle of intense light,
輝いてきてた 未来のために 託された 幸せと
shining brightly for the future, entrusted with happiness,
約束を越えて行くか 振り返らずに進むから
pushing past promises, moving forward without looking back.
前だけ向いて叫ぶから 心にほら おともして
I'll look straight ahead and shout, keeping a light in my heart,
遠い未来まで
until a distant future.
はい、ということで、ほむらでした！
So, that was "Homura"!
来てくれてありがとうございます！ パチパチ、てんきゅー！
Thank you so much for coming! Clap clap, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はぁ、緊張してきた。もうすごい緊張しちゃうね、今日。
Phew, I'm getting nervous. I'm getting so nervous today.
はぁ、結構これ、いま、はっ！もう25分経ったってマジか！
Wow, wait, it's already been 25 minutes? Seriously?!
すごい早いですね。あ、シー、シーですよ、みんな。気づいてないよね？
That's super fast. Shh, it's a secret, everyone. You didn't notice, right?
はい、というわけでね、もう30分ということで、まだまだ曲はね、実はいぎょう、用意しているし、
Anyway, it's already been 30 minutes, but we still have more songs prepared,
今日なんと、告知もね、用意しているので、告知は後半戦楽しみにしていてください！
and today we also have some announcements, so please look forward to the second half!
というわけでですね、次の曲も悲しい曲になってしまう、切ない胸がキュッてなっちゃう曲なんだけどね、
So, the next song is quite a sad song, a heartbreaking song that makes your chest tighten,
やっぱ、ボカロを1つ伝えたいなって思ってたので、今回はこれを歌いたいと思います。
but I really wanted to convey a Vocaloid song, so I'd like to sing this one.
それでは聴いてください。「レインストップ、グッバイ」
Please listen to it: "rain stops, good-bye".
面倒だと思いながら
Even though you thought that it was a bother,
君は僕にキスをした
you leaned down to kiss me.
泣き止まない 雨は穏やか
The rain didn't stop, it kept crying peacefully.
傘を閉じて 二人濡れた
I closed the umbrella, and we stood there soaking wet.
その声にもう少し 抱かれていたくて
I wish that your voice could embrace me just a little longer.
愛してる？
Do you love me?
今少し 口が止まったけれど
My words stopped for just a second, but...
叫んだ想いは きっと雨と一緒に
these feelings that I shouted will surely go down with the rain.
面倒だと思う間に
While thinking it was a hassle,
君は僕にキスをした
you kissed me.
鳴り止まない 雨は穏やか
The ceaseless rain is calm.
傘を閉じて 二人濡れたって
I closed the umbrella, and we got wet.
その声にもう少し 抱かれていたいって
I wanted to be held just a little longer in that voice...
届かない
It won't reach you.
雨が止め、君はまた
Rain stops, good-bye.
僕に背を向け歩き出す
walking away and turning your back on me.
何にも君は言わずに
You say nothing at all,
僕も特に何も言わず
and I don't particularly say anything either.
照りつける太陽に 痛みを感じて
Feeling the pain from the glaring sun,
濡れた髪が乾くまで ここで立ち竦んだ
I stood still here until my wet hair dried.
確かなことから逃げて つまずいて転んだ
Escaping from certainty, stumbling and falling,
時には空が見えた
even the sky was visible when I fell.
冷たい雨にも 嫌がらず打たれた
I was beaten by the cold rain without hating it.
君には届かない
It doesn't reach you.
叫んだ想いは きっと雨と一緒に
Surely, the thoughts I cried out
排水溝へ流れ行く
flow away into the drainage ditch.
どれだけ素敵な 歌に乗せたって
Even if I put them into such a wonderful song,
届かない
they won't reach you.
緑が舞う日も 茜に染まる日も
On days when greens dance or days stained with red,
もう隣には 君はいないって
you are no longer by my side.
それでも確かに 胸がざわついてる
Even so, my chest is definitely rustling,
君のいる方へ
heading towards where you are.
私もうやめた 世界征服やめた
I'm done, I've given up world domination.
今日の御飯考えるので精一杯
Figuring out tonight's dinner takes everything I've got.
もうやめた 二重生活やめた
I'm done, I've given up my double life.
今日からはそう掃除洗濯精一杯
Starting today, cleaning and laundry take everything I've got.
冬の香りの雑木林を抜けて
Passing through the winter-scented woods,
淹れ立て熱い紅茶も一杯
Enjoying a fresh cup of hot tea.
もうだめだ その日暮らしは嫌だ
I can't take living hand-to-mouth anymore.
ラブレター渡せないのも今日一杯
And today's my last day failing to hand over my love letter.
恋の微熱 37度5分
A fever of love: 37.5 degrees.
平熱 36度2分
Normal temperature: 36.2 degrees.
私もうやめた 破壊工作やめた
I'm done, I've given up sabotage.
妙な予感 振り払うので精一杯
Shaking off this strange premonition takes everything I've got.
もうやめた 無駄な抵抗やめた
I'm done, I've given up pointless resistance.
gone 甘く危険な日々に say goodbye
Gone, saying goodbye to bittersweet, dangerous days.
恋の微熱 37度5分
A fever of love: 37.5 degrees.
平熱 36度2分
Normal temperature: 36.2 degrees.
恋の微熱 37度5分
A fever of love: 37.5 degrees.
高熱 38度2分
High fever: 38.2 degrees.
とろけるキスは誰のため
Who is this melting kiss for?
おざなりキスは誰にする
Who gets this half-hearted kiss?
恥じらいキスは彼のため
This shy kiss is for him.
はちみつキスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキスは誰のため
Who is this melting kiss for?
おざなりキスは誰にする
Who gets this half-hearted kiss?
恥じらいキスは彼のため
This shy kiss is for him.
はちみつキスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキスは誰のため
Who is this melting kiss for?
おざなりキスは誰にする
Who gets this half-hearted kiss?
恥じらいキスは彼のため
This shy kiss is for him.
はちみつキスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキスは誰のため
Who is this melting kiss for?
おざなりキスは誰にする
Who gets this half-hearted kiss?
恥じらいキスは彼のため
This shy kiss is for him.
はちみつキスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキスは誰のため
Who is this melting kiss for?
おざなりキスは誰にする
Who gets this half-hearted kiss?
恥じらいキスは彼のため
This shy kiss is for him.
はちみつキスはどんな味
What does a honey kiss taste like?
とろけるキスは誰のため
Who is this melting kiss for?
秘密にする
Let's make it a secret,
初キスは彼の為
a first kiss is for him,
蜂蜜キスを神様に
and a honey kiss is for God.
はい、というわけで
So, anyways,
バーモントキスでした！
we started with "Vermont Kiss."
この曲覚えてくれてる人いますか？
Are there any of you who remember this song?
ふふっ！
Hehe!
ロボ子は、この曲をね、アレンジバージョンでなんですけど
Roboco did an arranged version of this song,
過去に動画で投稿してるんです。
and I've posted videos of it in the past.
気になってくれた人はね、ぜひぜひ動画の方も見ていただけると嬉しいな。
If you're interested, I'd really love for you to check out those videos too!
そして、覚えてるよ嬉しい、覚えてる？
And I remember it—yay, I remember it!
そう、誕生日のやつだね。
It's for your birthday, right?
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
そして、じゃじゃーん！桜、そして趣旨は
And the cherry blossoms and the concept are just...
添えるだけ、ふふっ！
adding them in, hehe!
ソファに埋めこんじゃった。おっと！
I ended up sinking into the sofa, oops!
そう、というわけでね、今回は久しぶりに桜ステージに来ました！
So, yeah, we came to a cherry blossom stage for a change.
みんな知ってます？
Does everyone know it?
ロボ子花見嫌いなんですけど、ここのバーチャル桜は大好きなんですよ、ふふっ！
I actually hate cherry blossom viewing, but I love virtual cherry blossoms, hehe!
そう、趣旨はこれ添えるだけ、ショートバージョンのやつ。
So, the point is just adding this short version.
可愛いでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
ちょっとなんか帽子に見える。
It kind of looks like a hat.
帽子に見える、あ、これは髪飾りだね。
It looks like a hat—oh, this is a hair ornament, right?
そう、花見嫌いなんですよ。バーチャルは好きなんですけどね。
So, I hate cherry blossom viewing. I love virtual ones, though.
そう、花粉があるからロボ子は嫌いなんです。そう！
So, since there's pollen, I hate it. Yeah!
はい、じゃあね、次の曲もね、まだまだあるので聴いてってほしいです。
Alright, well, we still have more songs coming up, so I hope you'll keep listening!
次も、まあ、お花にまつわるじゃ、お花にまつわるけどちょっと切ないかもしれない。
The next one is... well, songs about flowers are nice, but maybe a bit heartbreaking.
というわけで、聞いてください。「ドライフラワー」です。
So, please listen. It's "Dry Flower."
多分、私じゃなくていいね
Maybe it's better that it wasn't me
余裕のない二人だったし 気付けば喧嘩ばかりしてさ ごめんね
Before I knew it, we were always fighting, I'm sorry
ずっと話そうと思ってた
I've always wanted to talk
きっと私たち合わないね
I guess we're just not compatible
二人きりしかいない部屋でさ 貴方ばかり話していたよね
In a room with just the two of us, I was always talking about you
もしもいつか何処かで会えたら
If we could meet someday, somewhere,
今日のことを笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'd laugh about today
理由もちゃんと話せないけれど
I can't really tell you why, but
貴方が眠った後に泣くのは嫌
I hate it when you cry after you fall asleep
声も顔も不器用なところも 全部全部 嫌いじゃないの
Your voice, your face, your awkwardness—I don't hate everything about you
ドライフラワーみたい 君との日々も きっときっときっときっと 色褪せる
Like dried flowers, my days with you will surely fade away
多分 君じゃなくてよかった もう泣かされることもないし
Maybe it's better that it wasn't you, I won't make you cry anymore
「私ばかり」なんて言葉も なくなった
The words "It's always me" are gone
あんなに悲しい別れでも 時間がたてば忘れてく
Even if it was such a sad breakup, time heals all wounds, you know
新しい人と並ぶ君は ちゃんとうまくやれているのかな
I wonder if you're doing well next to someone new
もう顔も見たくないからさ 変に連絡してこないでほしい
I don't want to see your face anymore, so please don't contact me weirdly
都合がいいのは変わってないんだね
Convenience hasn't changed at all, has it?
多分、私じゃなくていいね
Probably it's better if it wasn't me,
余裕のない二人だったし
Since we were both running on empty,
気付けば喧嘩ばかりしてさ
Before we knew it, we were always fighting,
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
ずっと話そうと思ってた
I'd been meaning to talk to you for so long.
きっと 私たち合わないね
We're definitely just not meant to be.
二人きりしかない部屋でさ
In this room where it was just the two of us,
貴方ばかり話していたよね
You were always the only one talking.
もしもいつか何処かで会えたら
If we ever happen to meet somewhere someday,
今日の事を笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll be able to laugh about today.
理由もちゃんと話せないけれど
Though I can't properly explain the reasons,
貴方が眠った後に泣くのは嫌
I hate crying after you've already fallen asleep.
声も顔も不器用なところも
Your voice, your face, your clumsy ways—
全部全部 好きじゃないの
I dislike every single thing about you.
ドライフラワーみたい 君との日々も
Like dry flowers, the days I spent with you
きっと色褪せる
Will surely fade away.
はい、というわけで、花びら…でした！来てくれてありがとうございました！
So, that was... 'Hanabira'! Thank you for coming!
あ、いや、待って間違えた。ドライフラワーでした！次の、いや、いや、花びらきれいだなと思っただけです。
Ah, wait, I messed up. That was 'Dry Flower'! Next—no, no, I just thought the petals were pretty.
いや、すごい、花びらきれいですね。ドライフラワー歌わせていただきました！
Man, wow, the petals are so pretty. I sang 'Dry Flower' for you!
次の曲よ…あ、次の曲知って
I know the next song—
はい、で、実はね、ロボ子はね、この曲はね割と最近覚えた曲なんだけど、もうねすごい、アカシアが胸の奥のところからすごい実はリズムがハマって
So, actually, Roboko learned this song relatively recently, and y'know, from deep in my chest, the rhythm really clicked—
もうすぐに覚えた曲なんですけれど、時間経ってから
it's a song I learned right away, but after some time passed...
歌えてすごいい良かったです！うんうんうん…なんか、たまに、たまにスパムみたいなコメントあるけど、スパムじゃないのかな？大丈夫かな？バレへん、バレへん！
I'm so glad I got to sing it! Mhm, mhm... Sometimes there are spam-like comments, but is it not spam? Is it okay? They won't notice!
うーん、忘れるビーム！忘れてください。じゃあ、じゃあ、今みんなが忘れたっていうことで
Um, forgetting beam! Please forget it. Well then, considering that everyone just forgot...
次の曲いきたいと思います。じゃあ、次はね、もうライブで歌った、すごい思い出のある曲です。じゃあ聴いてください。
I'd like to move on to the next song. Next is a song with a lot of memorable live performances. Please listen.
はなびら
'Hanabira'.
ひとりきり見上げていた
Looking up all alone,
あの雲はすぐに消えていた
That cloud disappeared right away.
寂しさは いつも隣で
Loneliness was always right by my side,
私だけ見ていてくれた
Watching over only me.
人はなぜ 形求めて
Why do people seek out forms
会いたいと願うのでしょう
And wish to meet?
大切なあなたがいつも 笑っていてほしいだけ
I just want my precious you to always be smiling.
時を刻むリズムが
The rhythm marking time
春の風に揺れて
sways in the spring breeze.
追いかけないのは何故？見上げた霞み空
Why can't I catch up? I looked up at the hazy sky.
当たり前の温もりが 本当はこわかった
The ordinary warmth, I was actually scared of it.
痛み分け合いながら 重ね合わせた日々よ
The days we shared our pain and built together...
さよならを言えなかった
I couldn't say goodbye,
さよならを聞けなかった
I couldn't hear goodbye.
想い出に誘われた涙 めぐるめぐる
Tears invited by memories, spinning and spinning.
この命尽きゆくまで 君のこと見つめてたかった
Until this life runs out, I wanted to keep gazing at you.
花びらが落とした季節に 嗚呼 君を想う
In the season when flower petals fell, ah, I think of you.
いにしえの歌のように くぐり抜けた出逢い
Like an ancient song, an encounter we slipped through.
「通りゃんせ」もう戻れない 帰り道は独り
"Toryanse," we can no longer return, the way back is alone.
すれ違いの軌跡は 蒼く淡い夢模様
The trajectory of our passing was a pale, blue dream.
歩幅を合わせあう事 それだけでよかった
Matching our strides, just that was enough.
似た者同士だと笑い 似た者同士だと泣いた
Laughing that we were kindred spirits, crying that we were too.
たわいなく交わした言葉が めぐるめぐる
The casual words we exchanged, spinning and spinning.
もっと強くなれたなら 明日へも進めたかな
If I had grown stronger, could I have moved on toward tomorrow?
花びらを染めた君色は 嗚呼 色褪せない
The color of you that dyed the petals, ah, never fades.
さよならを言えなかった さよならを聞けなかった
I couldn't say goodbye, I couldn't hear goodbye.
きれいだね 君と見てた空
How beautiful, the sky I looked at with you.
めぐるめぐる 心から好きと言える
Spinning and spinning, being able to say I love you from my heart.
人にまた逢えるのかな
Will I ever meet someone like you again?
花びらが落とした季節に 嗚呼 君を想う
In the season when flower petals fell, ah, I think of you.
花びら舞い散るように あなたがそばにいてくれたから
Like dancing flower petals, because you were by my side,
大丈夫って伝えたい 強く慣れるよ
I want to tell you "it's alright," that I can become strong.
ひとりじゃ見えない景色を見つけたから
Because I found scenery I couldn't see alone.
さよならが言えなくても
Even if I couldn't say goodbye,
悲しみが消えなくても
Even if the sadness doesn't fade,
大切な時の流れ 今を生きて笑っていて
Living in the present through the flow of precious time, keep smiling.
あなたに出会えたから 大丈夫って伝えたい
Because I met you, I want to tell you "it's alright."
あなたに出会えなければ
If I hadn't met you,
やさしさも強さも知らないまま
I'd still know neither kindness nor strength.
ありがとうって伝えたい
I want to tell you "thank you."
信じられるよ 明日の私を
I can believe in tomorrow's me.
はかなき いとしい日々
Fleeting, precious days.
はーい、というわけで
Alright, so...
花びらでした！
That was "Hanabira"!
思い出してくれた人いますかね？ライブで歌った思い出のある曲です。
Did anyone remember it? It's a memorable song I sang at the live.
ネタバレじゃなかったよー。
It wasn't a spoiler!
拍手もいっぱいありがとう！スタンプもね、メンバーさんもいっぱい使ってくれてありがとうね。嬉しい可愛い！サンキュー！
Thank you so much for all the applause! And thank you members for using all those stamps too. So happy and cute! Thank you!
というわけで、なんと、もう50分になってしまった。
So, somehow, it's already been 50 minutes.
というわけで、ロボ子告知してもいいですか？
So, would it be okay for Roboco to make an announcement?
では、今回告知がなんと、あります！それはですね、こちら、どどん！
Now, there actually is an announcement this time! That is, here it is, ta-da!
ロボ子さん 活動三周年記念
[Roboco-san 3rd Anniversary]
1日から……
From the 1st...?
嘘ついた。
Just kidding.
22時からですね。
It's actually from 22:00.
22時から、えっと、ボイスのね、販売をしまーす！
Starting at 22:00, um, we'll begin sales of the voice packs!
なんと今回のほうはね、ボイス、え、記念ボイス、こちらのボイスは全部ASMRとなっております。
And for this time, the voice packs—uh, the anniversary voice packs—all of them are ASMR!
ASMRのシチュエーションの、え、ボイスと、そして,え、ブルジケ先生、ブルー先生のね、え、2層印刷のアクリルブロック、
We have ASMR situational voices, and also, um, illustrations by Blue.G-sensei, Blue-sensei's, um, double-layered acrylic block,
そして、同じくブルー先生のアクリルキーホルダーとなんといます！
and also an acrylic keychain by Blue-sensei!
え、こちら全部セットの特典では、ブルー先生のね、え、複製サイン入りのポストカードがなんと、ついてきます！
And for the complete set bonus, it actually comes with a postcard featuring a replica signature by Blue-sensei!
めちゃめちゃ可愛いんだけど、ちょっとさ、左側で、あのもう分かっちゃってるんだけど、アクリルブロックが一体どういうのって言うと、え、こちらですね、説明をどどーん！
It's super cute, but on the left side, you can kind of already see it—what exactly is the acrylic block? Well, here is an explanation, bada-boom!
はい、こんなの、立體的なの！
Yes, look at this, it's 3D!
可愛くない？
Isn't it cute?
これ。
This.
もうね、2種類のやつがあるんですけれども、両方ともブルー先生に変えていただきました。めちゃめちゃ可愛いんだ。
There are two types, and Blue-sensei drew both of them for us. They're super cute.
ニヤニヤしちゃうんだけど。
It makes me grin from ear to ear.
そう、で、今回実はですね、あの、花びらどうしてこの衣装にしたかっていうと、この衣装をね、合わせたかったっていうのがるので、
Right, and why did we choose this outfit with cherry blossom petals? Because I wanted to match this outfit,
涙メガネ、うさみみ、リボン、ポニーテール、そしてお正月衣装！
tear-drop glasses, bunny ears, a ribbon, a ponytail, and a New Year's outfit!
こちらですね。ふふふ、こんな感じのやつです。可愛いでしょう。そう、この衣装にしたんです。
Here it is. Haha, something like this. Isn't it cute? Yeah, that's why I chose this outfit.
そしてなんとね、もう1個の方はね、メイドさん。やっぱね、3周年記念はお祝い事だからさ、いっぱいねお菓子食べたいなってことで、欲張りセットです。ロボ耳じゃな、うさ耳なんだよな。そう。
And for the other one, it's a maid! Since the 3rd anniversary is a celebration, I wanted to eat lots of sweets, so it's a greedy set. Not robo-ears, but bunny-ears. Yeah.
猫耳メイドさんのアクリルキーホルダーとなっております。めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょう。こちらなんとね、
It's a cat-ear maid acrylic keychain. Isn't it super cute? And actually,
えもう50分になった時点で実実はブースさんのほうで発表されております。もう
Um, right at the 50-minute mark, it was actually announced on BOOTH. Already,
あ、お姉さんがお手早いことに、え、今更新していただくと、え、概要欄の方にリンクが、え、出てきている模様なので、ぜひぜひ見てみてください。
Ah, thanks to our speedy staff, if you refresh right now, links should be appearing in the description box, so please go check them out!
で、こちらのほうは、今はまだカートに購入っていうのはできないんですけれども、22時にね、なったら、え、買えるようになっておりますので、みんなぜひ購入してくれよな！可愛いだらゲットしてくれよな！
And for this one, you can't add it to your cart or purchase it just yet, but once it hits 22:00, you'll be able to buy it, so everyone please make sure to buy it! Go get your cute items!
うん。ASMRの方はね、今回3周年なんですけれども、ボイスの方出演をね、え、収録してみました。経由100で撮ってみて、音は結構いいと思います。
Yeah. For the ASMR, since it's our 3rd anniversary, I tried recording voice acting for it. We recorded with binaural mics, and I think the sound quality is pretty good.
でもね、ちょっと今回は、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、聞いてもらいたいなっていう感じですね。うん。
But you know, this time, I really, really want you all to listen to it. Yeah.
ちょっと、ちょっとシチュエーションをね、ロボ子が考えたんだけど、祈りと勢いとやってしまったので、これはまた生放送で詳しくまたみんなと話せたらいいなって思います。
I came up with the situation myself, but it was done with prayer and sheer momentum, so I hope we can talk about the details more on a live stream.
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
そう、見てほら、笑顔バージョン！可愛いでしょう？
Right, look, a smiling version! Isn't it cute?
これ、こんな感じ。
Like this.
すって。
Slide.
すって感じです。可愛い！可愛いロボコも早く飾りたいな。あ、見てしかも、今回サインがねなんと、あのいつものひらがなじゃなくて
Like that. Cute! I want to display the cute Roboco soon. Oh, look, also, this time the signature is—guess what—not the usual hiragana,
ローマ字になっています！ASMRはなんかちょっとさ、ちょっとなんか、え？みたいな感じのタイトルがあるの気づいた？あれ本当にすごい迷ったんだけど、
it's in Roman letters! Did you notice how the ASMR title has kind of a 'Huh?' kind of vibe to it? I was really, really hesitant about it,
遺せちゃいました！タイトルだけ、え、えなだけど全然そんなことないのね。あの全員聴けるやつなんでぜひぜひ聴いてみてくださいね。高性能になれます、あの薬は。
but I went ahead with it! The title might sound a bit, uh, questionable, but it's totally not like that. It's something everyone can listen to, so please give it a listen. That medicine will make you high-spec.
そうなんです。
That's right.
先生、あの……
Sensei, um...
残業代……逃げ……逃げちゃいました！
Overtime pay... I ran... I ran away!
上司さん、これあとで……変えてください！
Boss, please change this later!
あの……ロボコは、実は天才じゃなくて、し……なんですよ。ロボコの頭は、しなんですよ。
Um... Roboco isn't actually a genius, I'm a d—... Roboco's brain is just d—.
あーー！やっちゃったーー！
Aahh! I messed up!
いや、ロボコはまだ高性能になる薬飲んでないからさ、まだポンコツなんだよ。そう。
I mean, Roboco hasn't taken the medicine to become high-spec yet, so I'm still a clumsy bot. Yeah.
これはあとでサインちょっと変えます。
I'll change the signature a bit later.
というわけで、みんな今だけですよ、K.Oが見れるのは。
So everyone, right now is the only time you can see 'K.O'.
ね？そう、のりと勢いで変えちゃったらKって書いちゃった。
Right? Yeah, in the moment of hype and momentum, I ended up writing 'K'.
今はポンコツでも許してあげる。でもあとで高性能になるもん！
Forgive me for being clumsy right now. But I'll become high-spec later!
ろぼこみんな、みんなもね、あの
Roboco, everyone, everyone too, you know,
ROBOTTOよみたいな間違いないでね
like "ROBOTTO," don't get it wrong, okay?
ロボットはROBOTTOだし、
Robotto is spelled "ROBOTTO,"
ろぼこはROBOCOなのだね、
and Roboco is "ROBOCO," so...
みんな覚えておくんだぞ、ろぼことの約束にな？
everyone remember that, it's a promise with Roboco, okay?
こんだけね、こんだけ言えばと間違えればみんなもね間違いないでしょ。うん。
If I tell you this much, you guys won't get it wrong, right? Yeah.
というわけで、あと2分なんだけど、
That being said, there are about two minutes left,
歌ってる途中で、なんちゃおうの？
but while singing... what was I saying?
ぜひ聴いてみてく…聴いてじゃねぇや、購入してみてください。はい。
Please listen to— I mean, please purchase it. Yes.
それでは、最後は、もう最近のすごいお気に入りの曲、締めていきたいと思います。
And now, for the final song, I'd like to wrap up with one of my recent favorites.
これは、もうね、あたたかくなる曲で最後終わりたかったので、あたたかくなる曲を歌いたいと思います。
Since I wanted to end with a heartwarming song, I want to sing a heartwarming one.
それでは、聞いてください、「ぎゅっと」。
So please listen to "Gyutto."
手を繋ぐと体温が上がって
When we hold hands, our body temperature rises,
無邪気な笑顔につられて
coaxed by your innocent smile.
変な口癖真似してみたり
Mimicking your funny speech habits,
寝顔をじっと眺めていたら
or gazing intently at your sleeping face,
いつの間にか朝になってたり
before I knew it, morning had arrived.
特別はたままでいいよ
Special moments are fine just occasionally;
何気ない日常が私にとって大切で
ordinary days are so precious to me.
側居るだけでわかるの心からあなたが好きなんだ
Just being by your side makes me realize how much I love you from the bottom of my heart.
素直になれない ワガママな私だけど
I'm a selfish girl who can't be honest,
だから ねぇ、
so... hey,
あなたの大きな身体でぎゅっと抱き寄せて離さないで
hold me close and tight in your big arms, and don't let me go.
柔らかくて優しい声で
With a soft and gentle voice,
あたしの名前を呼んで
call my name.
それだけで時間は幸せだから一つ願いが叶うのなら
That alone makes me happy, so if one wish could come true,
あなたとこれからもずっとずっと隣にいれますように
I pray I can stay right by your side forever from now on.
悩んで落ち込んでいたり
When I'm worried and feeling down,
嫌なことで泣いていても
or crying over something unpleasant,
「大丈夫だよ」って
you always supported me
一番近くで支えてくれたね
right from the closest place, saying "It's gonna be okay."
そっと包み込んでくれる
You gently wrap around me,
私の弱いところ知ってるみたいに
as if you know all my weaknesses.
いつも隣にいてくれる
Always being right by my side—
あなたのおかげで
thanks to you,
側いるだけで落ち着くの
just being next to you calms me down.
あなたの彼女で幸せだって
Feeling so happy to be your girlfriend,
こぼれそうな好きの気持ち受け取ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll accept this overflowing love of mine?
ねぇ、
Hey...
あなたの大きな身体でぎゅっと抱きしめて離さないで
hold me tight in your big arms, and don't let me go.
柔らかくて優しい瞳で
With warm and gentle eyes,
あたしだけを見つめていて
just gaze only at me.
それだけで私は幸せだから
That alone makes me happy,
一つ願いが叶うのならあなたとこれからもずっとずっと隣にいれますように
so if one wish could come true, I pray I can stay right by your side forever from now on.
もしもこの先喧嘩しても価値観が違っても
Even if we quarrel in the future, or our values differ,
二人で乗り越えて行こうね
let's overcome it together.
全部全部ぎゅっと
Everything, everything, tight!
あなたの大きな身体でぎゅっと抱きしめて離さないで
Hold me tight in your big arms, and don't let me go.
温かくて優しい瞳で
With warm and gentle eyes,
あたしだけを見つめていて
just gaze only at me.
それだけで私は幸せだけど今日はあたしがぎゅっとさせてね
That alone makes me happy, but today, let me hold you tight.
一つだけ伝えたいことがあるのこれからもずっと大好きだよ
There's one thing I want to tell you: I will love you forever.
ぎっと君の手を掴んで走り出して
Holding your hand tight and starting to run,
小さなこの痛みを離さない
I won't let go of this small pain.
数メートル先の君の隣まで
To your side just a few meters ahead.
はい、というわけで最後は「ぎっと」歌いました！
So, with that, I sang "Gyutto" at the very end!
結構ガチ恋距離を意識してカメラ回してもらったんですけど
I had the camera focus on quite a close distance.
どうでしたか、みなさん！
How was it, everyone?
みんなどうだった？
How did everyone find it?
ガチ恋した？
Did you get gachikoi?
基本ガチ恋しないけどガチ恋した？本当？嬉しい！
I mean, I don't usually do gachikoi, but did you? Really? I'm so happy!
はい、というわけでなんとですね、22時22分22秒になっているので実は買えます！
So, since it's 22:22 right now, we are actually opening the merch sales!
みんなブースぜひぜひ購入してってくれよな！購入してくれますか？
Everyone, please make sure to purchase the merch from the booth! Will you buy it?
ガチ恋した？好きになりそう、嬉しい！嬉しい！
Did you get gachikoi? Will you fall in love? I'm so happy!
今日初めて見た人もね、いると思うので初めての方もね、気に入ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
I'm sure there are people here for the first time too, so I'd be so happy if you first-timers end up liking it as well!
スパチャもいっぱいありがとう！今度いっぱい読ませてね！
Thank you so much for the Super Chats too! I'll read plenty of them next time!
ありがとう！星マークも可愛い。
Thank you! The star mark is cute too.
買ったよ本当？はやっ！早い！歌声本当に好き、バラードライブ嬉しい、ありがとう！
Did you win? Really? It was so fast! Fast! I really love ballad songs, so I'm so glad the Ballad Live was a success! Thank you!
そう、というわけでね、ロボコも実は本当に3周年で
So, Roboco is actually reaching her 3rd anniversary...
しかももうあと1点何ヶ月とかしたらね、もう実はロボコ歳をとるんですよ、また1歳。なんと憧れの5歳になれるので
and in just 1.something months, Roboco will be turning a year old again, meaning I'll be turning 5 years old!
次の誕生日がとっても楽しみ。みんな5月のね、23日はね
So my next birthday is actually something to look forward to. Everyone, on May 23rd...
また別のことが色々できると思うので楽しみにしていてくださいね！そう、今ロボコは4歳なんです。
I'll be able to do various other things, so please look forward to it! So right now, Roboco is 4 years old.
そう、今4歳でみんなと3年間ね、一緒に配信をね、してって
So, being 4 years old and having done streams together with everyone for 3 years...
ソロライブもすごいいっぱい増えてって
and our ballad lives have grown so much too.
なんか何言おうかな、何言おうかなってすごい悩んでしまったんだけど、ロボコはその3周年をね、迎えたことによってバラードライブもね、実現できたのでもう本当にすごい嬉しいです！
I was wondering what to say, and I was worrying about it a bit just now, but since Roboco reached her 3rd anniversary, being able to make the Ballad Live a reality made me so, so happy!
あ、そうシノスケのタライになるの。そうシノスケのタライになる、嬉しい！
Oh, it's for Shinosuke's bucket! I'm so happy it's for Shinosuke's bucket!
そう、七五三ちゃん行こうね！えへん！行けちゃうもんね！
Make sure Shinosuke's bucket goes "Ehen", you can do it!
そう実現できたのでね、そうまだまだね、ライブはいろんな実験じゃないよ、実現ね！そうそう、長寿さんなの。そうなんだよ。
So, since it came true, still, our live is... not an experiment, a realization! Yes, that's what it is, longevity. That's right!
そう。うーん、いっぱい本当は、本当はこのご時世じゃなかったら
So, um, a lot... truly, if it weren't for these circumstances,
あの誰かをお呼びして一緒にやるっていうことを考えてたんだけど、やっぱりこのご時世だったからロボコオンリーのソロのバラードライブになってしまったんだけど
I had thought about inviting someone to do it together with me, but because of these circumstances, it ended up being Roboco's solo ballad live.
今度はね、ご時世が終わったらちゃんとゲストも呼んでデュエットもアリでライブがしたいと思ってますロボコは。
next time, once these circumstances are over, I really want to invite guests and even do duets for the live, that's what Roboco thinks!
なのでこれで終わりじゃなくて、これはロボコのYouTubeの中でのファーストライブっていうことで、次回は誰かを呼べたら嬉しいなって思い！
So, this isn't the end, this is Roboco's first live on YouTube, so I'd be so happy if I could invite someone next time!
だから医療チーム頑張ってくれ！
So, medical team, do your best!
次にはデュエットをやりのたいです！はい！
Next, I want to do a duet! Yes!
それじゃあみなさん、今日はロボコのバラードライブに来てくれてありがとうございました！
So everyone, thank you so much for coming to Roboco's Ballad Live today!
いっぱいスクショとかぜひぜひ見てってくれよな！感想とかロボコ後で見に行くからね！
Make sure to check out lots of screenshots and stuff! I'll be going around looking at them too, so everyone...
それではみんな、次の配信で会いましょう！
Let's meet at the next stream!
さようなら！おつろぼ！Thank you for watching! Thank you!
Goodbye! See you! Thank you for watching! Thank you!